Luis Navarro Del Angel

Hamilton, ON L8N 1X2 cell phone: (905) 379-8165 navarrol@mcmaster.ca, luisnavarrodelangel.net

PROFILE

Currently a PhD student in Communication, New Media, and Cultural studies at McMaster University. His current research intersects with live coding, Artificial Intelligence, and software studies. He also holds an MA in Communication and New Media from McMaster University and a Licenciatura in Music Composition from Fermatta Music Academy (Mexico). From 2010 to 2013 he worked at the Multimedia Center of the National Center for the Arts (Mexico) exploring the possibilities of free software and the paradigm of live coding. In 2012 he collaborated in the creation of the International Symposium of Music and Code /*VIVO*/ (Mexico). As part of the live coding collective RGGTRN he has performed at venues in Mexico, Spain (2014), France (2014), Switzerland (2014), and the UK (2016). As a member of the Cybernetic Orchestra directed by Dr. David Ogborn, he has performed at the International Conference on Live Coding, ICLC (Canada 2016), and NIME conference (Denmark 2017). This year he is co-chairing the International Conference on Live Coding 2017 (Mexico).

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

McMaster University, Hamilton, ON

PhD in Communication, New Media, and Cultural studies 2017 – PRESENT

McMaster University, Hamilton, ON

MA in Communication and New Media 2016 - 2017

Academia de Música Fermatta, Mexico City, Mexico

Licenciatura of Composition in Popular Music 2005 - 2013

ACADEMIC EMPLOYMENT

Teacher Assistant to Dr. Dyliana Mincheva

Course: *Introduction to communication PRESENT*

Teacher Assistant to Dr. Lewis Kaye

Course: *Introduction to digital audio Winter 2017*

Teacher Assistant to Dr. David Ogborn

Course: Introduction to digital audio

Fall 2016

Research Assistant to Dr. David Ogborn

Project: Browser-based Structure Editing for Live Coding Patterns Fall 2016 – Spring 2017

Research Assistant to Dr. David Ogborn

Project: Inner Ear: An interactive web-based sound-focused aural training technology Fall 2016 – present

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Elementary school teacher, Edu-kids, Mexico 2013-2015

After school music teacher, Rockville Academy, Mexico 2011-2014

Internship, National Center for the Arts, Mexico 2010-2013

SELECTED PRESENTATIONS AND LIVE CODING PERFORMANCES

Performance with the Cybernetic Orchestra- New Interfaces for Musical Expression, NIME (Denmark, 2017)

Panel on live coding and the visual – International Conference on Live Coding, ICLC (Canada, 2016) Performance with the Cybernetic Orchestra- International Conference on Live Coding, ICLC (Canada, 2016)

Performance with RGGTRN - *Algorave* at Open Data Institute, (UK, 2016)

Performance with RGGTRN - *Algorave* at Abject Gallery, (UK, 2016)

Performance with RGGTRN - *Algorave* at Ravensbourne College, (UK, 2016)

Performance with RGGTRN - Databit.me festival (France, 2014)

Performance with RGGTRN - La Escucha Errante electroacoustic festival (Spain, 2014)

Performance with Emilio Ocelotl + Luis Navarro + Anna Raszynska - *Source 2.0*, National Center for the Arts (Mexico, 2013)

Performance with RGGTRN – Museum of Contemporary Art, UNAM, (Mexico, 2012)

WORKSHOPS TAUGHT

- **"Music composition with programming languages"-** Universidad Autónoma de la Ciudad de México México, UACM (2015)
- **"Digital Audio and free Software" -** Universidad Autónoma de la Ciudad de México, UACM (Mexico, 2014)
- "Introduction to Fluxus" National Center for the Arts (Mexico, 2013)
- "Music creation with programming languages"- National Center for the Arts (Mexico, 2012)
- "Fluxus" Discoteca (Mexico, 2012)
- "Fluxus" National Center for the Arts (Mexico, 2011)
- "Introduction to real-time image manipulation" National Center for the Arts (Mexico, 2012)

SKILLS

Language – Spanish (native), fluent in English, intermediate French. **Computer skills-** Computer programming, familiar with Windows, Linux, and Apple OS, familiar with Digital Audio Workstations.